we know that exposure to certain agents can actually increase the risk of autism. In particular, there's a medication, valproic acid, which mothers with epilepsy sometimes take, we know can increase that risk of autism. In addition, there can be some infectious agents that can also cause autism. And one of the things I'm going to spend a lot of time focusing on are the genes that can cause autism. I'm focusing on this not because genes are the only cause of autism, but it's a cause of autism that we can readily define and be able to better understand the biology and understand better how the brain works so that we can come up with strategies to be able to intervene. One of the genetic factors that we don't understand, however, is the difference that we see in terms of males and females. Males are affected four to one compared to females with autism, and we really don't understand what that cause is. One of the ways that we can understand that genetics is a factor is by looking at something called the concordance rate. In other words, if one sibling has autism, what's the probability that another sibling in that family will have autism? And we can look in particular at three types of siblings: identical twins, twins that actually share 100 percent of their genetic information and shared the same intrauterine environment, versus fraternal twins, twins that actually share 50 percent of their genetic information, versus regular siblings, brother-sister, sister-sister, also sharing 50 percent of their genetic information, yet not sharing the same intrauterine environment. And when you look at those concordance ratios, one of the striking things that you will see is that in identical twins, that concordance rate is 77 percent. Remarkably, though, it's not 100 percent. It is not that genes account for all of the risk for autism, but yet they account for a lot of that risk, because when you look at fraternal twins, that concordance rate is only 31 percent. On the other hand, there is a difference between those fraternal twins and the siblings, suggesting that there are common exposures for those fraternal twins that may not be shared as commonly with siblings alone. So this provides some of the data that autism is genetic. Well, how genetic is it? When we compare it to other conditions that we're familiar with, things like cancer, heart disease, diabetes, in fact, genetics plays a much larger role in autism than it does in any of these other conditions. But with this, that doesn't tell us what the genes are. It doesn't even tell us in any one child, is it one gene or potentially a combination of genes? And so in fact, in some individuals with autism, it is genetic! That is, that it is one single, powerful, deterministic gene that causes the autism. However, in other individuals, it's genetic, that is, that it's actually a combination of genes in part with the developmental process that ultimately determines that risk for autism. We don't know in any one person, necessarily, which of those two answers it is until we start digging deeper. So the question becomes, how can we start to identify what exactly those genes are. And let me pose something that might not be intuitive. In certain individuals, they can have autism for a reason that is genetic but yet not because of autism running in the family. And the reason is because in certain individuals, they can actually have genetic changes or mutations that are not passed down from the mother or from the father, but actually start brand new in them, mutations that are present in the egg or the sperm at the time of conception but have not been passed down generation through generation within the family. And we can actually use that strategy to now understand and to identify those genes causing autism in those individuals. So in fact, at the Simons Foundation, we took 2,600 individuals that had no family history of autism, and we took that child and their mother and father and used them to try and understand what were those genes causing autism in those cases? To do that, we actually had to comprehensively be able to look at all that genetic information and determine what those differences were between the mother, the father and the child. In doing so, I apologize, I'm going to use an outdated analogy of encyclopedias rather than Wikipedia, but I'm going to do so to try and help make the point that as we did this inventory, we needed to be able to look at massive amounts of information. Our genetic information is organized into a set of 46 volumes, and when we did that, we had to be able to account for each of those 46 volumes, because in some cases with autism, there's actually a single volume that's missing. We had to get more granular than that, though, and so we had to start opening those books, and in some cases, the genetic change was more subtle. It might have been a single paragraph that was missing, or yet, even more subtle than that, a single letter, one out of three billion letters that was changed, that was altered, yet had profound effects in terms of how the brain functions and affects behavior. In doing this within these families, we were able to account for approximately 25 percent of the individuals and determine that there was a single powerful genetic factor that caused autism within those families. On the other hand, there's 75 percent that we still haven't figured out. As we did this, though, it was really quite humbling, because we realized that there was not simply one gene for autism. In fact, the current estimates are that there are 200 to 400 different genes that can cause autism. And that explains, in part, why we see such a broad spectrum in terms of its effects. Although there are that many genes, there is some method to the madness. It's not simply random 200, 400 different genes, but in fact they fit together. They fit together in a pathway. They fit together in a network that's starting to make sense now in terms of how the brain functions. We're starting to have a bottom-up approach where we're identifying those genes, those proteins, those molecules, understanding how they interact together to make that neuron work, understanding how those neurons interact together to make circuits work, and understand how those circuits work to now control behavior, and understand that both in individuals with autism as well as individuals who have normal cognition. But early diagnosis is a key for us. Being able to make that diagnosis of someone who's susceptible at a time in a window where we have the ability to transform, to be able to impact
sabemos que exponerse a ciertos agentes puede incrementar el riesgo de autismo. En particular, hay una medicina, el ácido valproico que las madres con epilepsia a veces toman, que sabemos puede incrementar el riesgo de autismo. Además, pueden haber agentes infecciosos que también causan autismo. Y una de las cosas en las que me centraré mucho es en los genes que pueden causar autismo. Me centro en esto no porque los genes sean la única causa de autismo, sino porque es una de las causas que podemos ya definir y podemos entender mejor la biología y entender mejor cómo funciona el cerebro de manera que podemos diseñar estrategias para poder intervenir. Uno de los factores genéticos que no entendemos, sin embargo, es la diferencia que vemos en términos de hombres y mujeres. Los varones se ven más afectados con autismo, con respecto a las mujeres en proporción de 4 a 1. Y en realidad no sabemos la causa de ello. Una forma en la que podemos entender que la genética es un factor es mirando algo llamado la tasa de concordancia. En otras palabras, si un niño tiene autismo, ¿cuál es la probabilidad que otro hermano en esa familia tenga autismo? Podemos ver particularmente esto en tres tipos de hermanos: gemelos idénticos, gemelos que en realidad comparten un 100% de su información genética y compartieron el mismo ambiente intrauterino con respecto a gemelos, a gemelos que en realidad comparten un 50% de su información genética, con respecto a los regulares, hermano-hermana, hermana-hermana, que también comparten un 50% de información genética pero no el mismo ambiente intrauterino. Y cuando observamos los índices de concordancia, una de las cosas sorprendentes que pueden ver es que en los gemelos idénticos, su tasa de concordancia es del 77 %. Sin embargo, no es del 100%. No es que los genes sean responsables de todos los riesgos de autismo, pero representan una gran parte de ese riesgo, porque cuando vemos a los gemelos fraternales, la tasa de concordancia es solo del 31%. Por otro lado, hay una diferencia entre esos gemelos fraternos y los hermanos, sugiriendo que hay exposiciones comunes entre los gemelos fraternos que pueden no ser compartidos comúnmente con los hermanos solos. Esto nos brinda algunos datos de que el autismo es genético. Bien, ¿y cómo de genético es? Al compararlo con otras condiciones con las que estamos familiarizados, cosas como el cáncer, enfermedades del corazón, diabetes, de hecho, la genética juega un rol mucho mayor en el autismo con respecto a cualquiera de otras condiciones. Pero con esto, no nos dice cuáles son los genes. No nos dice ni siquiera en un niño si es un gen o una combinación potencial de genes. Y en realidad, en algunos individuos con autismo ¡es genético! Es decir, que es un solo, poderoso y gen determinístico que causa el autismo. Sin embargo, en otros individuos es genético, esto es, que es en realidad una combinación de genes en parte con el proceso de desarrollo el que a fin de cuentas determina el riesgo de autismo. No sabemos de ninguna persona, necesariamente, cuál de las dos respuestas es hasta que escarbamos más profundamente. Así que la pregunta sería, ¿cómo podemos empezar a identificar qué genes exactamente son? Y permítanme plantear algo que puede no ser intuitivo. En ciertos individuos, que puedan tener autismo por una razón que es genética pero todavía no a causa de autismo presente en la familia. La razón es porque en ciertos individuos, que en realidad pueden tener cambios genéticos o mutaciones que no se transmiten de la madre o del padre, sino que comenzaron en ellos, mutaciones que están presentes en el óvulo o el esperma al momento de la concepción pero que no se transmitieron generación tras generación en la familia. Y en realidad podemos usar esa estrategia para ahora entender e identificar los genes que causan el autismo en esos individuos. De hecho, en la Fundación Simons, tomamos 2 600 individuos que no tenían antecedentes familiares de autismo y tomamos a esos niños y a sus madres y padres y los usamos para tratar de entender ¿cuáles eran los genes que causan el autismo en esos casos? Para hacer eso, de hecho, tuvimos que ser capaces de ver toda la información genética y determinar cuáles son esas diferencias entre la madre, el padre y el niño. Haciendo esto, me disculpo, voy a usar una analogía obsoleta de las enciclopedias más que Wikipedia, pero voy a hacerlo para tratar y ayudar a mostrar el punto de cómo hicimos el inventario, tuvimos que ser capaces de ver una cantidad masiva de información. Nuestra información genética está organizada en un conjunto de 46 volúmenes, y, teníamos que ser capaces de revisar cada uno de esos 46 volúmenes, porque en algunos casos con autismo, solo falta realmente un volumen. Tuvimos que hilar más fino, sin embargo, y tuvimos que abrir dichos libros, y en algunos casos, el cambio genético era más sutil. Podría haber sido un solo párrafo que le faltaba, o incluso, más sutil que eso, una sola letra, una en tres mil millones de letras que se cambió, que se alteró pero que tuvo profundos efectos en términos del funcionamiento cerebral y que afecta el comportamiento. Al hacer esto con las familias, fuimos capaces de revisar aproximadamente 25% de los individuos y determinar si existió un solo factor genético poderoso causante del autismo en esas familias. Por otro lado, hay un 75% que todavía no hemos descubierto. Aún así, mientras lo hacíamos fue realmente una lección de humildad, porque nos dimos cuenta de que no había simplemente un solo gen para el autismo. De hecho, las estimaciones actuales son que hay entre 200 y 400 genes diferentes que pueden causar autismo. Eso explica, en parte, porque vemos un espectro tan amplio en términos de sus efectos. Aún cuando hay muchos genes, existe algún método para la locura. No es simplemente al azar 200, 400 genes diferentes, que de hecho encajan. Ellos encajan en una vía. Encajan entre sí en una red que empieza a tener sentido ahora en términos de cómo funciona el cerebro. Estamos empezando a tener un enfoque de abajo hacia arriba donde identificamos esos genes, esas proteínas, esas moléculas, entendiendo cómo interactúan entre sí para que la neurona funcione, entendiendo cómo las neuronas interactúan juntas para que el circuito funcione, y entender cómo funcionan estos circuitos para controlar el comportamiento, y entenderlo, tanto en las personas con autismo así como en los individuos que tienen cognición normal. Pero un diagnóstico temprano es clave para nosotros. Poder hacer ese diagnóstico en alguien que es susceptible en un tiempo, en una ventana donde tenemos la capacidad de transformar, para poder tener un impacto
that growing, developing brain is critical. And so folks like Ami Klin have developed methods to be able to take infants, small babies, and be able to use biomarkers, in this case eye contact and eye tracking, to identify an infant at risk. This particular infant, you can see, making very good eye contact with this woman as she's singing "Itsy, Bitsy Spider," in fact is not going to develop autism. This baby we know is going to be in the clear. On the other hand, this other baby is going to go on to develop autism. In this particular child, you can see, it's not making good eye contact. Instead of the eyes focusing in and having that social connection, looking at the mouth, looking at the nose, looking off in another direction, but not again socially connecting, and being able to do this on a very large scale, screen infants, screen children for autism, through something very robust, very reliable, is going to be very helpful to us in terms of being able to intervene at an early stage when we can have the greatest impact. How are we going to intervene? It's probably going to be a combination of factors. In part, in some individuals, we're going to try and use medications. And so in fact, identifying the genes for autism is important for us to identify drug targets, to identify things that we might be able to impact and can be certain that that's really what we need to do in autism. But that's not going to be the only answer. Beyond just drugs, we're going to use educational strategies. Individuals with autism, some of them are wired a little bit differently. They learn in a different way. They absorb their surroundings in a different way, and we need to be able to educate them in a way that serves them best. Beyond that, there are a lot of individuals in this room who have great ideas in terms of new technologies we can use, everything from devices we can use to train the brain to be able to make it more efficient and to compensate for areas in which it has a little bit of trouble, to even things like Google Glass. You could imagine, for instance, Gabriel, with his social awkwardness, might be able to wear Google Glass with an earpiece in his ear, and have a coach be able to help him, be able to help think about conversations, conversation-starters, being able to even perhaps one day invite a girl out on a date. All of these new technologies just offer tremendous opportunities for us to be able to impact the individuals with autism, but yet we have a long way to go. As much as we know, there is so much more that we don't know, and so I invite all of you to be able to help us think about how to do this better, to use as a community our collective wisdom to be able to make a difference, and in particular, for the individuals in families with autism, I invite you to join the interactive autism network, to be part of the solution to this, because it's going to take really a lot of us to think about what's important, what's going to be a meaningful difference. As we think about something that's potentially a solution, how well does it work? Is it something that's really going to make a difference in your lives, as an individual, as a family with autism? We're going to need individuals of all ages, from the young to the old, and with all different shapes and sizes of the autism spectrum disorder to make sure that we can have an impact. So I invite all of you to join the mission and to help to be able to make the lives of individuals with autism so much better and so much richer. Thank you. (Applause)
el cultivo, el desarrollo del cerebro es fundamental. Así que colegas como Ami Klin han desarrollado métodos para ser capaces de tomar infantes, bebés, y usar marcadores biológicos, así, el contacto visual y seguimiento ocular, para identificar a los infantes en riesgo. Este infante en particular, se puede ver, hace muy buen contacto visual con esta mujer mientras ella está cantando "Witsi, Witsi Araña", de hecho no desarrollará autismo. Sabemos que este bebé está a salvo. Por el contrario, este otro bebé desarrollará autismo. En este niño en particular, pueden ver, que no hace un buen contacto visual. En lugar de enfocar los ojos y tener esa conexión social, mirando la boca, mirando la nariz, mirando en otra dirección, pero nuevamente sin conexión social, y siendo capaces de hacer esto en una escala muy grande, examinando a los bebés, a los niños por autismo, a través de algo muy robusto y confiable, será muy útil para nosotros para poder intervenir en una etapa temprana cuando podemos tener mayor impacto. ¿Cómo vamos a intervenir? Probablemente será una combinación de factores. En parte, en algunos individuos, probaremos y usaremos medicamentos. Y así, de hecho, la identificación de los genes del autismo es importante para nosotros para identificarlos objetivamente, para identificar cosas que puedan tener impacto y estar seguros de que eso es lo que tenemos que hacer en el autismo. Pero esa no será la única respuesta. Más allá de solo medicamentos, utilizaremos estrategias educativas. Los individuos con autismo, algunos están cableados un poco diferente. Aprenden de otra manera. Absorben su entorno de otra manera, y debemos ser capaces de educarlos de una manera que les sirva mejor. Más allá de eso, hay muchos individuos en este salón con grandes ideas sobre las nuevas tecnologías que podemos utilizar, desde dispositivos para entrenar el cerebro para hacerlo más eficiente y compensar las áreas en las que tienen algunos problemas, hasta cosas como los Lentes Google. Imaginen, por ejemplo, a Gabriel, con su torpeza social, podría usar Lentes Google con un auricular en la oreja, y tener un entrenador capaz de ayudarlo, ayudarlo a pensar acerca de las conversaciones, iniciar conversaciones, ser capaz de tal vez, algún día de invitar a una chica a una cita. Todas estas nuevas tecnologías ofrecen enormes oportunidades para que seamos capaces de impactar a las personas con autismo, pero todavía tenemos un largo camino por recorrer. Por mucho que conocemos, hay mucho más que no sabemos, por lo que invito a todos Uds. a ayudarnos a pensar en cómo hacerlo mejor, de como comunidad usar nuestra sabiduría colectiva para hacer una diferencia, y, en particular, para los individuos de familias con autismo, los invito a unirse a la red de autismo interactivo, a ser parte de la solución a esto, porque necesitará de muchos de nosotros para pensar en lo que es importante, y hará una diferencia significativa. Mientras pensamos en algo que sea potencialmente una solución, ¿qué tan bien funcionará? ¿Es algo que marcará la diferencia en sus vidas, como individuos, como una familia con autismo? Necesitaremos personas de todas las edades, desde jóvenes a adultos, y con todas las formas y tamaños de los trastornos del espectro autista para asegurarnos que podemos tener un impacto. Así que los invito a unirse a la misión y a ayudar a hacer las vidas de las personas con autismo mucho mejores y más ricas. Gracias. (Aplausos)